Finding Aid for the King Vidor Papers LSC.0934
UCLA Library Special Collections
King Vidor papers
1920-1965
UCLA Library Special Collections
Vidor, King, 1894-1982
LSC.0934
7.0 Linear Feet (14 boxes)
King Wallis Vidor (1894-1982) made over fifty feature films and received five Academy Award nominations before retiring from films in the late 1950s. His directorial debut was The turn in the road (1919), but he is best known for The big parade (1925), The champ (1931), and Duel in the sun (1947). The collection contains annotated scripts, correspondence, photographs, and ephemera for 22 films Vidor produced or directed including The big parade, Duel in the sun, Northwest passage, and Stella dallas.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of King Vidor, 1966.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9934671443606533
Biography
King Wallis Vidor was born February 8, 1894 in Galveston, Texas; made fifty-six feature films in forty years; married Florence Arto, 1915 (divorced 1925); married Eleanor Boardman, 1926 (later divorced); married Elizabeth Hill; his directorial debut was The turn in the road (1919); made Hallelujah! (1929), the first sound picture with an all black cast; best known for The big parade (1925), The crowd (1928), The champ (1931), Stella Dallas (1937), and Duel in the sun (1947); wrote an autobiography, A tree is a tree (1953); retired from films in the late 1950s; taught a graduate cinema class during the 1960s at UCLA; received Edinburgh Film Festival award for career achievements, 1964; after receiving five Academy Award nominations during the course of his career, he was granted a special award for his innovations in cinema, 1979; died of congestive heart failure, Paso Robles, California, on November 1, 1982.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of materials related to Vidor's career as a motion picture director and producer. Contains annotated scripts, correspondence, photographs, and ephemera for 22 films including The big parade, Duel in the sun, Northwest passage, and Stella dallas.
Related Oral History
The following oral history is available through the UCLA Library Center for Oral History Research:
Filming of "Duel in the Sun": Recollections of Ray Rennahan, Lee Garmes, and King Vidor [oral history transcript] / Ray Rennahan, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1969. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Motion picture producers and directors -- United States -- Archives.; Film scripts.; Silent films -- Production and direction -- United States -- Archives.; Vidor, King, 1894-1982--Archives.
- Three Wise Fools (M-G-M, 1946). (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Completely annotated continuity.
  Completely annotated scenario by King Vidor.
- The Strangers' Return (M-G-M, 1933). (Box 1)
  Typed copy of novel with King Vidor's holographic notes for adaptation.
  Fully annotated treatment.
- So Red the Rose (Paramount, 1935). (Box 1)
  One final annotated script.
  One annotated censorship script.
- Wild Oranges (Metro-Goldwyn, 1924). (Box 1)
  Fully annotated working script and production breakdown.
  Script and holographic notes.
- H.M. Pulham, Esqire (M-G-M, 1941). (Box 2)
  Fully annotated working script.
  Annotated script before J.P. Marquand arrived.
  Photographs -- clippings.
- The Texas Rangers (Paramount, 1936). (Box 2)
  Progression of scripts including production orders, and casting notes -- annotated.
  Rare personal photographs.
- Wedding Night (United Artists, 1935). (Box 3)
  Fully annotated script.
- His Hour (Metro-Goldwyn, 1924). (Box 3)
  Original treatment by Elinor Glyn -- holographic notes.
- Hallelujah! (M-G-M, 1929). (Box 3)
  Annotated script.
- Stella Dallas (United Artists, 1937). (Box 3)
  Annotated script and working notes.
  Silent picture detail upon which remake was based.
  Clippings and publicity.
- The Jack Knife Man (First National, 1920). (Box 4)
  Key album of photographs.
- Miscellaneous
  - Production and correspondence, In re Northwest Passage., 1939-1941. (Box 4)
  - Production and correspondence, 1937-1959. (Box 4)
  - Southern Storm. (Box 4)
    Original manuscript -- annotated.
  - Museum of Modern Art -- pamphlets. (Box 4)
  - The Standard, 1933. (Box 5)
  - The Hollywood Reporter, Thirteenth Anniversary Edition. (Box 5)
  - The Cast, February 1933. (Box 5)
  - The Cast, October 1932. (Box 5)
  - Witch Of The Wilderness (Original, never produced). (Box 5)
  - Six miscellaneous folders. (Box 5)
- Proud Flesh (Metro-Goldwyn, 1925). (Box 6)
  Working script, fully annotated, including production notes, cuts and revisions.
- The Big Parade (M-G-M, 1925). (Box 6)
  Holographic production notes; instructions to assistant director; cutting notes; grosses; prop lists; daily reports -- fully annotated.
- Miracles Can Happen (United Artists, 1948). (Box 6)
  Fully annotated script progression including all changes and additions.
- Duel in the Sun (Selznick, 1946). (Box 6)
  Original continuity sketches -- water color, pencil, pen and ink.
  Clippings and reports.
- Comrade X (M-G-M, 1940). (Box 7)
  Fully annotated working script including all changes and revisions and progression of scripts.
- The Patsy (M-G-M, 1928). (Box 7)
  Fully annotated treatment and script.
- The Fountainhead (Warner Brothers, 1949). (Box 7)
- Northwest Passage (M-G-M, )., 1940 (Box 8, Box 9)
  Fully annotated working script with additions and notes.
  Fully annotated dialogue cutting continuity.
  One script with changes.
  An earlier script by Robert Sherwood -- not used.
- The Citadel (M-G-M, 1938). (Box 9, Box 10)
  Fully annotated progression of scripts, including working script.
  Miscellaneous holographic research and notes.
  Folder of photographs.
- Our Daily Bread (United Artists, 1934). (Box 11, Box 12)
  Holographic production notes and correspondence.
  Interviews, reviews, advertising.
  Two albums of photographs.
  Photographs of King Vidor (re The League of Nations Medal).
- American Romance (M-G-M, 1944). (Box 13, Box 14)
  Progression of scripts leading to final script. Includes retakes, outtakes, fully annotated working script with holographic notes, changes, revisions, cuts and research.
  Holographic file on Vincent Lawrence (writer) and Holographic file on William Ludwig (writer).
  Miscellaneous correspondence with studio, agent, etc.